♪Trapped in this tiny world♪
♪I'm crushed into dust♪
♪I meddle around without any mercy♪
♪I'm my own pawn♪
♪I sigh at my fate♪
♪Numerous people are under my control♪
♪All the sand is washed away♪
♪An old dream fades♪
♪A bumpy path lies ahead♪
♪Traps within traps, I never make mistakes♪
♪I take a risk at every step♪
♪Even in disputes, I break through with my life♪
♪Schemes within schemes, I prison myself♪
♪Each link swaps bluff and truth♪
♪The world is my Weiqi game board♪
♪Everything's just fleeting♪
♪The play begins♪
♪No return is expected♪
♪The flame is gone, whether we win or lose♪
♪The wind never ceases. I hold the reins♪
[Ashes To Crown]
[Adapted from Xixing's novel, Empress of the State of Chu]
[Episode 15]
The... the Lord of Xiaonan
rebelled.
Return at once
to tell Her Highness.
Your Highness,
Xiao Xun killed the dispatch riders.
We've lost contact with the Capital.
All post houses along the way
are under his control.
Rumors reached the Capital.
Northern Desert Army breached Bailang Pass.
Yunzhong will fall in three days.
They'll march
for the imperial city.
How's the Capital?
Fifty thousand troops in the capital camp
and one hundred thousand nearby.
Why should we fear Xiao Xun?
What we fear is that the commoners
believe Xiao Xun's lie
to defend the Capital.
In that case,
he can rightfully lead his troops
into the city.
If Xiao Xun enters the Capital,
Yu's life will be in danger.
Xie Yanfang is by Yu's side.
He's ruthless.
But his clan relies on Yu.
Xie Yanfang will protect him.
You're right.
Xie Yanfang still has
a crucial trick.
This time,
he'll definitely make this move.
Get Xiaoman to me.
Yes.
[Chu Zhao]
Whatever you want me to do,
let me know.
All post houses along the way
have been cut off.
I want you to take your men
to bypass the post houses
and head for the Capital.
Then, escort my cousin Chu Tang
and her family
out of the Capital.
Why all the trouble?
Why don't we let her
bring the news of the frontier
to the Capital?
Who would believe
a bandit?
The public opinion in the Capital
completely favors Xiao Xun
who "guards" His Majesty.
Then what is the problem
of Chu Tang's family?
Chu Lan is a mere civil official.
What danger
justifies all the effort
to save him?
In Anping Rebellion,
Xiao Xun used my uncle
to kill His Majesty.
Now, he's the key witness.
All parties will fight over him.
I count on you.
Don't worry. Leave it to me.
What about you?
To the Capital?
No.
I'm going somewhere else.
Father.
Mother.
You were separated half your lives.
Now you're finally reunited
in the underworld.
Sadly,
I have to leave.
I'll keep defending the city
Father left undefended.
I'll continue the war
Father left unfinished.
Mother dreamed of peace
all over the world.
I'll make it come true.
[The Capital]
I've heard Xiao Xun
has reached Baili Pavilion.
A noble heir like him
is always reliable.
I believe soon,
he'll rescue the Capital from danger.
He's been practicing martial arts since childhood
and he leads elite troops.
Hope he'll arrive soon.
Since General Chu died,
Yunzhong troops
have been in utter chaos.
They won't bother with the Capital.
Luckily, His Highness
is on his way here.
Fair enough.
The Grand Princess is brave,
but she's too young.
We have to count on real royal members
to guard the Capital
and protect our state.
Jiang,
the weather is lovely.
Take Tang out for some fresh air.
The tea has gone cold.
The conversation is ironic.
If she stays longer,
she'll feel sick.
Goodbye, then.
Jiang.
Why is she angry again?
Mr. Xiao Xun is noble.
Had General Chu not built
the city walls at great cost...
Had Her Highness not guarded Wangcheng...
You couldn't be sitting here,
enjoying cold tea,
or satirizing them.
I advise you
hold your tongues.
Jiang,
I have a favor to ask.
We're friends. Don't say that.
What is it?
I need help from your family.
Mr. Xie, to what do I owe
the honor of this visit?
I'm here to ask you, Mr. Deng.
Do you really choose
to throw your life away with Xiao Xun?
What do you mean?
I don't understand.
Xiao Xun has reached Baili Pavilion.
He keeps releasing messages
that he's coming to protect His Majesty.
He expects a wide-open city gate
where people line up to welcome him.
But do you know
how we will
end up
if the city gate is open to him?
Since it's the will of people,
you should try to stop
the people in the Capital.
What's the point of coming here
to stop me?
Looks like you're determined
to side with Mr. Xiao.
They're within the defense line.
The Capital is just ahead.
If His Majesty still refuses
to open the gate,
their advance will be
an unauthorized move
and willful treason.
After they enter the city,
you might as well
find an excuse
to kill them.
You know people's will is irreversible.
In their eyes,
Xiao Xun
is a meritorious protector
they're expecting.
If His Majesty still refuses,
people will complain.
So, Mr. Xie,
what do you intend to do?
We must make Xiao Xun
a rebel again.
Are you saying
you'll prove his father's treason?
Only in this way
can we stop Xiao Xun from entering town.
If he attacks by force,
all the people will know
that the court has no choice
but to fight back.
If the war breaks out,
the court will be rightful.
We'll have no more worries
and all the people will submit.
Then no one will question
Yu's throne.
Then how will you prove
the treason of the Lord of Xiaonan?
Do you know
Chu Lan was bribed by Xiao Xun
to poison Yu
in Chu Mansion?
You'll use Chu Lan as a scapegoat?
Have you considered?
If Chu Lan gets in trouble,
the Chu Family will be implicated.
Then the Grand Princess
can hardly stay out of trouble.
Great achievements
require great sacrifices.
Only when we expose
Xiao Xun's scheme
can the two of us
keep the city gate
firmly shut.
Isn't that so?
I'm still curious about one thing.
Xiao Xun wrote a letter
to you.
What was in...?
After all that talking,
I finally get it.
You think
Chu Lan isn't enough.
You'll also get me involved
to prove their treason.
But have you thought about this?
Is it a righteous war?
Is it justified?
You care.
His Majesty cares.
But I don't care.
Don't try to keep your clan innocent
by ruining my reputation.
You're wrong again.
I just came here
to give you a favor.
Instead of keeping some secrets buried,
why not turn them into your achievements?
My Lord.
Xie Yanfang wants to kill two birds with one stone.
[To open the gate or not]
Get ready.
I'll see Chu Lan tonight.
[Chu Mansion]
My Lord, we looked everywhere.
No one is in.
We asked the neighbors.
Nothing unusual was noticed.
During the day, Chu Tang
even had tea with some ladies.
As she came home,
she vanished into thin air.
We may have early plans,
but someone's always earlier.
As soon as we had the idea,
they had run away.
How could they leave so perfectly?
Theoretically,
when Chu Zhao is away,
Chu Lan should be isolated
from the court.
And Chu Lan doesn't look
like he can read the situation.
Is it possible
that Her Highness
sent them a message?
Xiao Xun intercepted all the messages.
How did Chu Zhao manage
to send one?
Xie Yanfang used up all his schemes.
But his own ally
stabbed him in the back.
Send a message to Mr. Xie.
Tell him the witness he longs for
has fled.
[Xie Residence]
How come he fled?
The Grand Princess has
more political support than I imagined.
Of the clans who have ties with Chu Family,
five left the city yesterday.
Some said
they went to rural houses.
Some said they had an outing.
And...
Today, three ladies
met with Chu Tang in the day.
Shall we pursue them?
It is time for us
to go out and visit someone.
[Side residence of Zhou family]
Be careful, Mr. Chu.
Come on, sweetheart.
Hurry.
Come, Tang.
Jiang,
thank you.
My pleasure.
Don't thank me.
Without my grandfather's approval,
I couldn't have helped you
even if I wanted to.
Jiang,
I need you
to help my family leave.
Why me?
Shouldn't you
beg some clan heads?
I was told to ask them.
But big clans have deep connections
with shared interests.
I...
I thought about it.
You're the only one
I can entrust my life to.
At the Hai hour tonight,
my carriage will
pick you up at the back door of Chu Mansion.
I shall remember
your great favor.
Go get some rest.
Come on, Tang.
Your uncle and his daughter
are so useless.
We shouldn't have
expected them to bring glory.
You...
Luckily, our daughter is farsighted
and gets along with other noble ladies.
Madam, you sound so proud.
Do you really think
her mere friendship can
get you through the city defense?
The Grand Princess
arranged deceptive schemes
and sent bandits
to clear enemy sentries.
Otherwise, you wouldn't
have come here alive.
You... You are...
Yes.
We're the bandits,
whom people like you
despise most.
Her Highness sent me
to get you.
Don't yell.
Nod and I'll let you go.
Lord of Xiaonan isn't a defender,
but a usurper.
To reveal Xiao Xun's true colors,
the court will dig up the evidence
your father nearly killed
the young emperor.
Danger.
Her Highness said
the heads of these clans
are reliable.
Go ask them for help.
[Chu Zhao]
Darling.
Xiaoman, let's leave.
This is a bestowal to Jiang's ancestors.
It must be on record with the Ministry of War.
Within half a day,
we will all get caught.
Tang,
how could you still
doubt the Zhou Family?
Just now, Miss Zhou seemed
she truly wanted to help us.
Father,
Jiang truly wants to help us.
That's why
we can't get her involved.
But they...
Stop lingering.
Go with me.
Let's go.
Hurry.
But they...
Oh, Darling.
[Zhou Bing, Minister of Rites]
My Lord,
Chu Lan's trail is gone.
Mr. Zhou, you really made
very cunning moves.
No offense,
but I gave up a piece to get ahead.
Mr. Xie,
you're still so enigmatic when playing Liubo.
I wonder what you're fighting for
in this round.
When the Lord of Xuan played with me,
he wrongfully killed a loyal man over one piece.
In today's game,
I'm fighting for His Majesty's life.
Lord of Xiaonan and his heir
nearly took
His Majesty's life.
Chu Lan is the witness.
So, I hope you will
help His Majesty
to reveal the truth to people.
Over generations,
my clan has been a bystander.
Mr. Xie,
you don't need to probe me like this.
I don't know
where Chu Lan is.
Mr. Zhou,
you must know no one can be
a bystander in chaotic times.
My Lord,
we've searched.
Nothing.
Yes.
Sorry for the offense.
I'll take my leave.
Oh.
It's too windy tonight.
Remember to close your windows.
Mr. Xie,
please see yourself out.
My Lady, be careful.
Father.
The carriage
that took them out of town
is back.
Shall we make early preparations?
If Mr. Xie
really finds out something,
then...
Jiang did something reckless.
But since we promised to help,
we won't complain.
Between the Grand Princess
and Mr. Xie,
there will be
a long game of strategy.
[Xie Residence]
Welcome, Mr. Deng.
We are honored by your presence.
This orchid is very delicate.
No strangers shall touch it.
You tend this flower so well.
Sadly,
its roots have rotted.
It barely appears to bloom.
You've searched the whole day.
Have you found what you're after?
The Grand Princess is so far away,
but big clans give her generous support.
She does have great influence.
You didn't come here
just to satirize me,
did you?
Do you know where Chu Zhao is?
She's riding at full speed
toward Xiaonan.
Does she think Xiao Xun
will retreat when his father is trapped?
How childish.
Her Highness will suppress the rebels on His Majesty's behalf.
What's wrong with it?
Her Highness has great influence.
Since she dares,
she must be confident enough.
Yeah.
You and Her Highness
used to have the same goal.
You were both against Xiao Xun.
But you insist
on using Chu Lan as a scapegoat
and getting her clan involved.
Obviously,
Chu Zhao wouldn't agree.
That's a bit much, Mr. Deng.
As long as you approve the edict
that Xiao Xun instigated Chu Lan
to poison the imperial grandson,
Her Highness will be suppressing the rebels
with a valid reason.
I'm helping her,
aren't I?
Have you heard about this?
An orchid dies, but its fragrance will linger.
Someone
only gets in the way when he's alive.
Mr. Xie, you have
a very clever plan.
I'll take my leave.
Mr. Deng.
We're just serving the state
by cutting out the deadwood.
What's this?
Why is Zhao guilty?
Don't, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
this edict says
her uncle Chu Lan is guilty.
Did you forget?
He tried to poison you back then.
So, Her Highness
took you away from her family.
So, Chu Lan is really guilty.
Then why did no one
tell me about it?
Chu Lan
is Zhao's uncle.
If he's guilty,
she will be implicated.
Now, the situation is complicated.
Lord of Xiaonan and his heir
intend rebellion.
Xiao Xun is coming as a defender.
Our people support him.
Ministers want the city gate
to be opened too.
But if he leads his 100,000 troops into town
without firing a single shot,
we won't be able to resist.
The casualties will be terrible.
What we should do now
is let the entire world know
the sins of Xiao Xun and his father.
Then we'll all rise against them.
You're bullying Zhao.
You're bullying her
just because her father is gone.
Yu,
no one is bullying
your sister.
If she were here now,
she would do the same.
The post houses have been cut off.
But the men I sent out
learnt something.
Xiao Xun intercepted a victory report.
Not long ago,
Chu Zhao led a raid
against Northern Desert Royal Army,
driving them back a hundred li.
And later,
the enemy relaunched an attack.
Once again, she led troops
to crush them.
She did?
What's more,
on hearing Xiao Xun was leading troops
to surround the Capital,
she led forces to attack Xiaonan.
Do you know why?
"Besiege Wei to rescue Zhao."
I've read about that.
That's right.
So you don't need to worry.
Your sister
fears nothing.
No one can bully her easily.
She's defending our state
and our people.
Even when her uncle is guilty,
she won't be implicated.
Do you trust me?
I trust you.
[Xiaonan Prefecture]
I never thought
I could have a battle
against the Grand Princess.
How dare she besiege us
with only a few thousand troops?
A warrior's daughter?
I think
the great reputation
of Chu Ling
will just be ruined
by his daughter
who has a swollen head.
Your Lordship,
don't bother with her.
I'll go teach her a lesson.
Your Lordship,
the Grand Princess wants to talk.
The Grand Princess?
What's she doing here?
Since she wants to talk,
tell her
I have trouble walking
and can't go out.
However,
my gate is always open to her.
She can come anytime.
[Xiaonan]
We both know
it's an ambush.
If you enter his mansion,
you'll be walking straight into the lion's den.
If Xiaonan holds you
as a hostage,
the Capital will face a tough choice.
You worry too much.
Mr. Deng and Xie Yanfang
can't wait for me to die for the state.
Believe it or not,
they've even prepared
my posthumous title.
This is no child's play.
Are you really sure?
I know what worries you.
Lord of Xiaonan is so cunning
that he even rebels
in the name of guarding His Majesty.
[Xiaonan]
If the Grand Princess
dies in his mansion,
guess how history will judge him.
He will be a traitor,
whether he likes it or not.
So...
Will you
take this gamble with me?
Of course.
Not to mention his mansion,
I'll even follow you
to the underworld.
This time,
we'll all live well.
We must live.
[Nan]
What an impressive mansion.
Look at the scale.
He's so obviously showing
his ambition to be the Emperor.
Then
I'll kill that hope of his.
How could we reject the tea he offered?
You've got some spine, Miss Chu.
Don't you fear I may put something
in the tea?
I am
the Grand Princess of State.
I can fight battles with you
and slaughter your men.
If I were to die from poisoned tea,
people in the world
would laugh at you.
Even if I were bloodthirsty,
I would know
I should keep worthy generals alive.
Besides, I've admired General Chu.
He's gone.
I still count on you
to inherit his legacy.
How would I try to kill you?
You flatter me.
In that case,
please withdraw your troops
that are besieging the Capital.
Don't let common folks die
in your fight for the throne.
As a general's daughter,
you must be familiar with military classics.
Have you read about this?
Glory for one, death for thousands.
New dynasty rises, the old one falls.
Someone must sweep away
the incense ash
before burning new incense.
If His Majesty
grants you the Golden Seal
and feudal sovereignty,
will you stop the war?
Your Highness,
when His Lordship
can get the Imperial Seal,
why would he need the Golden Seal?
You offered a great deal
to make me retreat.
But how dare a woman like you
grant me feudal sovereignty?
When I grant something,
you will get it.
Now, I understand.
You aren't persuading me
for the young emperor
or the ministers in the court.
You're trying to stop me
for the sake of the people.
What a saint you are.
I'm not a saint.
I am
the Grand Princess of State.
I won't see this state fall apart.
Like I said,
I've admired General Chu
and I think highly of you.
What about
you and I working together?
How?
If I become the Emperor,
Xun will be the Crown Prince
and you'll be the Crown Princess.
Then you'll be the Empress.
I can also grant you
the command over frontier troops,
unrestrained by the court's Tally.
Do you agree?
So, being Xiao Xun's empress
can get me such great power.
I'm not kidding.
I know.
You really mean it.
Too bad, though.
Am I offering not enough?
Feel free to make any other requests.
I have only one request.
I request you
to stop the war.
You need to understand one thing.
I can persuade you.
You're in no position to persuade me.
I'm not here to persuade you,
but threaten you.
With what can you threaten me?
Xiao Xun.
Speaking of him,
he has still kept
your birthdate card.
He knelt for three days and nights,
swearing to marry no one but you.
But you requested to annul your engagement.
Xun still hasn't figured out
what he did wrong.
Today,
I know the answer.
You must be Commander Xie.
I've heard a lot about you.
You're as remarkable as people say.
During the coup,
you led a few guards to defeat ten thousand troops.
You are a real hero.
Your Lordship,
don't be ridiculous.
I broke off my engagement
for the people of our state,
not for romance.
Narrow-minded as you are,
how can you fight for the throne?
What a sharp tongue.
If I remember correctly, Mr. Xie,
your brother
also has great ambitions.
If one day you meet in armed conflict,
whose side will you take?
I pledge loyalty to His Majesty,
the Grand Princess,
and the State of Chu.
Anyone who hurts the imperial heir
or the Grand Princess
will be my enemy.
You're truly a hero who is worth a hundred men.
Remarkable, indeed.
Do you know
he isn't the only one
who is worth a hundred?
There's also the Longwei Army.
The Longwei Army?
You must've heard
about the Longwei Army.
They put down the rebellion
while outnumbered.
My father
devotedly trained them.
They move like ghosts
and scatter around in disguise.
How can you be sure
there aren't any in your mansion?
If you agree to retreat,
I'll pretend nothing happened.
So, this is how you threaten me.
You want to use the Longwei Army
to kill my son
as well as me.
You can take this
as a gamble.
Five thousand soldiers outside the town.
Five thousand of the Longwei Army in town.
If they
join hands,
how will you handle it?
Someone.
Get the rooms ready.
Give Her Highness a warm reception.
The secret guards in this room
can be withdrawn.
With poor inner power
and uneven breath,
they're useless.
Your Lordship,
Xie Yanlai
is no ordinary man.
When he's around Chu Zhao,
we can hardly hurt her.
Ning Kun,
you have no idea.
Chu Ling and the late emperor
trained the Longwei Army.
The scariest thing
about them is...
We don't know who they are
and we don't know
when or where they'll appear.
They're unpreventable.
Tell Xun to be on guard.
Yes.
In such a big courtyard,
I can't even hear a bird.
It's eerily quiet.
Careful.
Lord of Xiaonan has great taste.
He even uses the best tea
for mere visitors.
Too bad, though.
The tea got cold.
We know it's an ambush
and we should be more cautious.
What if he poisoned the tea?
He wouldn't dare.
Not now, at least.
What he wants
is to be legitimate.
If I die in his place,
have a guess.
Will people spit
and drown this place?
You know the Longwei Army
isn't in Xiaonan.
But you bluffed just like that.
Didn't you fear that he could
see through you?
Let me tell you this.
What makes the Longwei Army terrifying
is that people believe
they're everywhere.
Don't worry.
Someone's having a harder time.
His Lordship is cautious by nature.
Without a perfect plan,
he wouldn't act rashly.
He sent Xiao Xun to the Capital
because he thought the time was right.
The calmer we are,
the more he will
doubt his own judgment.
When he thinks it's not the right time,
he'll ask Xiao Xun to retreat.
So, just now,
you were trying
to break his will,
making him think
his plan wasn't perfect.
Then he'll lose his cool
and withdraw.
That's right.
So, Jiu,
don't be impatient.
We'll just wait.
We'll wait patiently
until he makes his decision.
I've heard
this is the best scenic spot
all over this mansion.
Let's not waste
his hospitality.
♪Broken walls and withered branches, trapped in the mire♪
♪Yet still striving to reach for the sky♪
♪My pride is torn down and my body is sacrificed♪
♪The spark smolders in the crack♪
♪And roars in the blaze♪
♪Burning the cold night until daybreak♪
♪Fate imprisons me♪
♪But I won't beg the abyss for mercy♪
♪Even if hope is faint, I remain proud♪
♪A mayfly will cross the ocean, however long it takes♪
♪However it ends up, I'll go my own way♪
♪With no fear of the distance♪
♪Born from decay, fireflies still burn♪
♪With sword in hand, I'll pierce the dawn♪
♪Let these scars all over me become♪
♪My new pride♪
♪Peril is everywhere in the palace♪
♪Yet I smile to nobody but you♪
♪Amidst the chaos♪
♪I'll always be with you♪
♪The spark smolders in the crack♪
♪And roars in the blaze♪
♪Burning the cold night until daybreak♪
♪Fate imprisons me♪
♪But I won't beg the abyss for mercy♪
♪Even if hope is faint, I remain proud♪
♪A mayfly will cross the ocean, however long it takes♪
♪However it ends up, I'll go my own way♪
♪With no fear of the distance♪
♪Born from decay, fireflies still burn♪
♪With sword in hand, I'll pierce the dawn♪
♪Let these scars all over me become♪
♪My new pride♪